MATTHEW WIDDOP

[REDACTED] ♦ Website
Birmingham, UK ♦ LinkedIn
[REDACTED] ♦ GitHub

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am currently studying a bachelor's degree in Computer Science at the University of Birmingham, currently averaging a first. I am primarily interested in software development, cyber security and networking. I have a clear record showing dedication to improving the student experience throughout the university and making positive change to benefit students and staff alike.

EDUCATION

University of Birmingham, Birmingham

September 2021 - Present

B.Sc. Computer Science

- Object Oriented Programming (96%).
- Full Stack Application Development (100%).

University of Birmingham, Birmingham

September 2020 - July 2021

B.Sc. Engineering & Physical Sciences Foundation Year

- Elementary Computer Programming (99%)
- Mathematics (1) (68%)
- Further Mathematics (2) (67%)
- Calculus (71%)
- Statistics & Data

Craven College, Skipton

September 2018 - July 2020

Level 3 Extended Diploma in Information Technology (D*D*D*)

South Craven Secondary School, Cross Hills

September 2013 - July 2018

13 GCSEs Grade 9 to $5(A^* \text{ to } C)$

EXPERIENCE

Guild of Students, UoB

May 2022 - Present

Student Groups Assistant

Birmingham, UK

· Responsible for customer service and general administration tasks with the student groups team in the Guild.

 $\begin{array}{c} \textbf{Max 2019 - Present} \\ \textit{Accountant} \end{array}$ $\begin{array}{c} \textit{Leeds, UK} \\ \end{array}$

· All financial management, reporting and filing for the company.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS & SKILLS

Programming Languages Java, Python

Markup Languages LaTeX, HTML, CSS, Markdown, PHP, JS, SQL, XML, JSON

Protocols & APIs REST, SSH, SFTP Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL

OSs Windows, Ubuntu, Kali, Tails

Tools Git, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ, Excel, Google Sheets, Jupyter

CERTIFICATIONS, HONOURS AND AWARDS

Personal Skills Award (Advanced)

September 2022

· The Personal Skills Award (PSA) is the University of Birmingham's optional employability programme, designed to develop professional skills and attributes in preparation for graduate employment. Upon completion of the award, an assessment is undertaken which will demonstrate exceptional commitment to developing skills and fostering professional practice.

EXTRA CURRICULAR

University of Birmingham Senate

June 2022 - Present

UG Student Representative

Birmingham, UK

· Responsible for representing all 25,000 undergraduate students at UoB to the Senate.

College of Engineering and Physical Sciences, UoB

June 2022 - Present

College Representative

Birmingham, UK

· Responsible for representing all 10,000 students within the college of EPS to the college level committees.

Misconduct and Academic Appeals Committee, UoB

May 2022 - Present

Nominated Student

Birmingham, UK

· Responsible for considering evidence and making decisions as part of the committee.

Poker Society, UoB

April 2022 - Present

Social Secretary

Birmingham, UK

· Responsible for organising and managing social events for the Poker Society at UoB.

Jiu-Jitsu Club, UoB

March 2022 - Present

Captain

Birmingham, UK

· Responsible for the management and organisation of the Jiu Jitsu club at UoB Sport and Fitness with more than 30 members and 3 instructors.

Computer Science Society, UoB

February 2022 - Present

Industrial Liaison

Birmingham, UK

· Collaborated with industry contacts to secure sponsorship agreements for the society.

School of Computer Science, UoB

October 2021 - Present

 $Student\ Representative$

Birmingham, UK

- · Responsible for representing all 3,000 students in the SoCS to the following:
 - School Committee
 - Education Committee
 - Staff-Student Forum

REFERENCES

Name: [REDACTED]
Email: [REDACTED]
Phone: [REDACTED]

Name: [REDACTED] Email: [REDACTED] Phone: [REDACTED]

Relationship: [REDACTED]

Relationship: [REDACTED]